KARAN **OBEROI**

FULL STACK WFB **DEVELOPER**

CONTACT



(951) 880-7001



koberoi1017@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/karanobe



github.com/karanobe



karanobe.com/

ABOUT ME

I am developer committed to building beautiful and meaningful things. I was originally drawn to programming as a creative outlet, but got hooked on solving hard problems and writing complex algorithms. I have full stack experience, ranging from configuring servers, building server-side applications, to developing robust front-end JavaScript applications. As a full-stack developer, I have visibility on a project from start to finish, and I enjoy creating software architecture plans, and executing those plans with an emphasis on testing.

KEY SKILLS

HTML5	BOOTSTRAP
CSS	REST
RUBY	ANGULARJS
JAVASCRIPT	RAILS
POWERSHELL	JSON
JQUERY/AJAX	MVC
T-SQL	HEROKU
POSTGRESQL	RSPEC
MS SQL SERVER 2016	AGILE WORKFLOW

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Apr 2015 - Present

SELF-EMPLOYED

- Design and develop interactive websites for user experience using **JavaScript**
- Develop UI/UX strategies using wireframes and mockups for small and medium-sized enterprises
- Create illustrations using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- Experienced backend developer using Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, SQL, **PostareSQL**
- Fluent in frontend web technologies: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, jQuery and AJAX
- Extensive practical experience in Test-Driven Development, Object-Oriented Design, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, and Agile workflow
- Immersed in 1500+ hours of coding, using pair programming, iterative software development, documentation research, debugging, and best practices for optimization

Production Support Engineer July 2017 - Sep 2017

EDOCUMENT SOLUTIONS

- Create reports to fulfill information requests using MS SQL Server 2016, with emphasis on business intelligence
- T-SQL development and optimization (querying, scripts, stored procedures) for multiple production environments
- Scripting automation tasks and complex algorithms for internal efficiency using PowerShell
- Apply Agile methodologies and tools, including JIRA and Confluence
- Experience with Directory Servers e.g. LDAP

Operations Manager

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

LA MINA DE ORO

- Developed, improved, and implemented procedures for warehouse and sales staff
- Create reports to fulfill information requests using QuickBooks Enterprise 2016, with emphasis on business intelligence
- Transitioned inventory management system from QuickBooks to Fishbowl
- Implemented barcode scanning system for proper inventory organization

Co-Founder/Developer

Apr 2015 - Aug 2016

MUZE APPLICATIONS

- Generated UI for customer-facing website, using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and ¡Query
- Daily correspondence with over 1000 investors, raised seed funding
- Directed the company in keeping with the vision outlined by the Board of Directors
- Developed, reviewed, and refined company's business strategy, and executed those strategies

EDUCATION

DevBootcamp

Nov 2016 - May 2017

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

Ruby Full Stack, testing strategies, and algorithmic techniques

UC Irvine

Sep 2009 - Jun 2013

BACHELORS, SOCIAL ECOLOGY: PLANNING, POLICY, & DESIGN